Eric Bárbaro Utrera Sust

Professional software developer, Project Manager and academic.



Address: Edificio 31 apto 8 Pueblo Griffo, Cienfuegos

Age: 28

Phone: +5358073436

E-mail: ebutrera910322@gmail.com

LinkedIn:https://www.linkedin.com/in/eric-utrera-529665109?trk=nav responsive tab profile pic

Professional software developer, project manager and academic with more than 4 years of experience, in constant search for excellence. Specialized in the development of web applications, desktop applications and databases. Information Architect, Software Analyst Developer and Tester. Lover of research and continuous learning.



EXPERIENCE





Position in the company

Universidad de las Ciencias Informáticas Septiembre de 2011 -2015

Developer with results in the productive and scientific sphere standing out in software development as a frontend and backend programmer. Database designer and developer, web interface designer and analyst. Projects: Cuban Search Engine, System for the Virtual Community of Symfony in Cuba (DSymfony), Web Portal for the province of Cienfuegos, System to identify key words in scientific articles, Computer tool for the recovery of digital images published in the Web, Web Portal for the Sexual Education Center Cuba, Web Portal for the Pioneer Magazine.

- Professional Software Developer (Programmer Analyst Consultant) in University of Information Sciences. Tasks:
 - Development of web backend applications with PHP (Symfony) and Java technology.
- Development of frontend web applications with Bootstrap, Angular, EmberJS and React technology.
- Development of desktop applications with Java, C++ and C # technology.
- Advanced database development with PostgreSQL, MySQL and MongoDB technology.
- Development of information recovery systems with Apache / Solr and Apache / Nutch technology.

Position in the company

Universidad de las Ciencias Informáticas Septiembre de 2015 - 2018

- Research and Postgraduate Advisor at the University of Information Sciences where he provides consulting and attention to several software development research groups. (6 months of experience)

Commercial Advisor at the University of Computer Sciences where he specializes in the area of commerce developing offers for clients and studying the market of web technologies. (4 months of experience)

-Project Manager Platform c.u.b.a (Cuban search engine) (+ 2 years of experience)

- Instructor Professor at the University of Computer Sciences. Tasks: You teach the subjects of: Advanced Object Oriented Programming (P1), Artificial intelligence Programming using
- data structures (P2 and P3), Web Programming, Web Development Framework, Web
- Development with AngularJS, EmberJS and React.

EDUCATION



Universidad de las Ciencias Informáticas, Cuba

SKILLS AND KNOWLEDGE

Computer Science Engineer 2011 - 2015

Politécnico de Informática, Cuba

Technical Media 2006 - 2009

Languages y frameworks

- Java
- ▶ PHP
- JavaScript
- HTML
- CSS
- **C**#
- C++
- Symfony
- Angular
- ▶ EmberJS
- React
- NodeJS
- Bootstrap
- Android.

Tools

- InfluxDB.
- Grafana.
- LKE.
- Telegraf.
- PostgreSQL.
- MySQL
- MongoDB,
- (Visual Microsoft Office Basic),
- Apache Solr
- Biq Data
- Ontology Networks
- Apache Jena, Apache Nutch, Apache Stambol

Specialties

- Project management Information architect.
- Semantic Web
- Information retrival
- Free software.
- Web development with Symfony,
- Angular, Ember and React. Artificial intelligence.
- Development with Java and C #.
- Academic specialized in
- programming.

LANGUAGES AND SOFTWARE •



- Spanish (Native Language)
- English (Intermediate)
- French (Medium)

